

Yücel Uzun

XR Developer

yuceluzun@windowslive.com

in

yuceluzun



ujell.github.io

Education

M.Sc. Media Informatics

2014-2018

RWTH Aachen

B.Sc. Computer Engineering

2009-2013

Yildiz Technical University

Skills

Mixed Reality

Unity C# HoloLens

iOS und Android Quest

Mobile Applications

iOS Swift Objective-C

Other

TypeScript Node.js

About me

I am an extended reality designer, developer and enthusiast with a computer science background.

I love exploring new technologies, creatively solving new UX challenges, experimenting and I am not afraid of using or mixing different solutions. This has served me well as an iOS developer in the early 2010s, then during my Master's studies and now in my work at Fraunhofer FIT.

At the moment I mainly develop in Unity with C#, but I also use many other tools and programming languages in my daily work, from Node.js to Adobe Creative Suite.

Experience

Fraunhofer FIT

Research Associate

08/2018 - today

Student Assistant

05/2015 - 07/2018

At Fraunhofer FIT, I've worked on a wide range of XR projects, from planning to deployment, in various fields, including health, culture and marketing. I am currently working on the "IndustrieStadtpark" project, in which we are extending real production environments with the industrial metaverse and 5G.

I also had the opportunity to explore a wide variety of technologies and tools other than Unity. I do server development with Node.js and TypeScript and manage those servers, I've implemented WebRTC based video chat applications multiple times in different platforms, developed dashboards with React.js and AngularJS, wrote Python programs, developed native Windows, iOS, WatchOS and tvOS apps.

Open Business Software Solutions

iOS App Developer

09/2013 - 08/2014

As a consulting developer, I developed native iOS applications for our clients.

Besides the internal applications, the most important application I developed was the corporate client app for the third largest private bank in Turkey.

Yildiz Technical University

Probabilistic Robotics Group 09/2012 - 07/2013

Mobile Application Development Team

01/2012 - 07/2012

Gamester

Internship 07/2012 - 08/2012

Languages

